<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Meyer</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="www.jackcmeyer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 15:37:21 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 15:37:21 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Reflection: The Volkswagen Ethical Scandal</title>
        <description>
A reflection
If I were an engineer on the Volkswagen project, I would have tried my hardest to make sure that no ethical violations were happening. To make sure that didn’t happen, I would have tried the following steps to ensure that no violations were happening. First, I would have talked to my direct manager about my findings. I would start here, to make sure that my manager is aware of the issue. If I were to deem that my manager is in on the scheme, then I would go to the HR department of the company. If the HR department doesn’t listen to my concerns, then I would go seek legal help. In the meantime, I would refuse to implement anything that surrounds this algorithm. I would hope that my manager was unaware of what was happening because of naivety and would help resolve the problem. However, if the manager was in on it, I would hope that HR would help out and do what is in the best interest of the company and protect themselves against potential ethical violations. If neither party was willing to help solve the problem, then I would seek legal help and have them bring action against the company to stop the unethical and illegal actions.

I believe that the engineers at Volkswagen continued to implement algorithms they knew were unethical because they had no other options. For example, there might have been clauses in contracts that prevented them from talking to anybody about things that happened at work. This might have scared off many engineers in talking to people outside of the company. Next, there was probably a toxic relationship between developers and middle managers which prevented the engineers from talking with their managers. Without a good relationship between developers and managers, it would be very hard for developers to communicate concerns about the company’s direction and decisions to their manager. Finally, there was probably a lack of options for communicating with the HR department of the company. The engineers probably felt that the HR department was not going to help the engineer and protect the company rather than the employee. They probably felt that if they were to talk to anyone within the company about this ethical violation, they would lose their jobs. This caused everyone to stay quiet and just do the work they were told to do. Which resulted in a huge ethical violation.
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/blog/2017/12/01/ethics-reflection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/blog/2017/12/01/ethics-reflection/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>hammer.io (senior design project)</title>
        <description>
hammer-io is a tooling suite for developing microservices in Node.js. It provides a command line application and web application to generate projects, a web application to view statistics about the application, and a monitoring framework to view the status of your application.

Microservice development requires doing many different project configurations, which takes away time from developers from actually working on the part of the application that is going to make money. One of our goals at hammer-io is to eliminate most of the time and issues with project setup by giving you a opinionated, yet customizable, approach to setting up your Node.js application.

With microservice development, instead of one application running in production being developed, there is now many applications. This makes it very difficult to track things like build statuses, open issues, test results, uptime statistics, data flow statistics, or health statuses for the application. Another one of hammer-io’s goals is to make this process pain free be curating all of this data into a application.

On the hammer-io team, I lead the Software Architecture conversations, play the role of a tech lead, and a developer on the server side of our tool suite. Through my experience on the team, I have learned what it’s like to create a software architecture and maintain and enhance it through the evolution of the project. I also learned how to set up a development workflow through the use of feature branches, pull requests, and code reviews. I learned how to set up a DevOps workflow using GitHub, TravisCI, and Docker. Finally, I learned how to lead a team of developers to complete hammer-io for our client.

Are you curious about our work? You can follow development of our command line application, Tyr, here and our web application, Yggdrasil, here. Want to install our command line application? Visit our npm page!
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2017/10/05/hammerio/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2017/10/05/hammerio/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Reflection: My General Education at Iowa State University</title>
        <description>
A reflection
Over the course of my 4 years at Iowa State, I have taken many general education courses which helped change and shape my world view and understand engineering problems and how the world may or may not view the solution. As a Software Engineer, the products we create have the ability to change the way people interact with the world, see the world, and use the world. It is important that we are well versed in many different subject areas so we c an fully understand the people that are using our products.

Throughout my career as an engineer, I hope that I have the ability to create solutions which are going to enable people to do things in their lives in ways that they were previously not able to. Right now, my current passion is in healthcare and I hope to create solutions which are going to decrease the cost of medical care, while at the same time raise the standards of care. I hope to work in an environment where everyone shares these goals and where everyone has a passion for developing unique, cutting edge solutions in the healthcare field. I hope to work in a fast-paced paced environment, where we are able to act on changing requirements quickly and efficiently, an environment where people push others to succeed rather than working for their own gain, and an environment which is collaborative, lighthearted, and welcoming.

Taking general education courses have helped me understand the worldview of other people and understand where their views come from. I took a class about the different religions in the United States. This class helped me understand many different religions, and different religions symbols and values. I also took a post-civil war history class which allowed me to get an understanding of how modern America was shaped and what the core values the people in our country have. Finally, I took a philosophy course which allowed to understand the different way people think. These courses allowed me to view an engineering problem in ways that I was not able to before. I can think of a problem and a solution and have a better understanding of how different people interact with the solution. I have more of an understanding of the needs and wants of different people in society and I am able to apply those to the problem I am trying to solve.

I have also learned how to effectively communicate about the problem and solution. Through a technical writing course and speech course, I have gained the skills needed to write clear and concise thoughts. As an engineer, it is important to be able to be able to reason about problems and solution, write about them, and discuss the solution.

When solving engineering problems, it is important to understand how other members of society will view the product. It is also important to understand what people value and what they need, and how the solution can eliminate the user’s needs while making sure to not infringe on their value system. It is always important to consider gender, race, and religion and ensure that any solution doesn’t violate any values that different people of different background may have. Some software engineering application may reach a global audience, so it is important to consider cultures outside my own. My general education classes helped me understand what people from the other parts of the world may be thinking as well.

Overall, my general education classes have had a positive impact on my life inside and outside of engineering. I have gained a clearer picture about different cultures, religions, and genders; different ways of thinking; and United States history.  Finally, I’ve learned how to more effectively communicate my thoughts in writing and in speech.

General Education Courses I’ve Taken


  
    
      Course Title
      Course Number
    
  
  
    
      The Earth
      GEOL 101
    
    
      Introduction to Philosophy
      PHIL 201
    
    
      Survey of United States History II
      HIST 222
    
    
      Principles of Microeconomics
      ECON 101
    
    
      Introduction to Weather and Climate
      MTEOR 206
    
    
      Religion in America
      RELIG 210
    
    
      Technical Communication
      ENGL 314
    
    
      Fundamentals of Public Speaking
      SP CM 212
    
    
      Introduction to Sociology
      SOC 134
    
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/blog/2017/10/05/general-education-reflection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/blog/2017/10/05/general-education-reflection/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Reflection: My Cumulative Education at Iowa State University</title>
        <description>
As my time at Iowa State comes to a close, I’ve taken some time to reflect on different aspects of my time here. In this post, I will reflect on my coursework, resources that I used to complete coursework, extra curricular activities, my work going forward, and changes I would make if I had to do my undergraduate degree again.

During my time at Iowa State, I feel like I have had ample experience learning how to design and implement engineering solutions to software problems. Through courses like Software Architecture, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Software Practices, and other intro courses, I have had the opportunity to learn how to design a system and have also been given the tools to implement those designs. The ability to design and execute these system plans can be exemplified through projects I have made throughout my coursework. I also feel that the Software Engineering Curriculum has done a good job of understanding the ethics behind making a decision and what potential side effects could come about if an unethical decision is made. This topic is covered in many courses such as Project Management, Software Requirements, Senior Design, and our Portfolio course. As students, we have had the opportunity to view different ethical standards and do case studies on ethical scandals of the past. However, there is one area where I believe the curriculum is lacking. Unfortunately, there is a lack of conversation about how software solutions can be used to solve global or societal issues. Sometimes, there seems to be a lack of connection between what we do in the coursework and how it could be used to solve problems in the real world. If I could change one thing, it would be to have any semester long project based course take a real look at how their application or tool could be used to solve a problem in society. It doesn’t have to be an application to cure cancer or stop poverty, but it would be a huge benefit to the student if they were required to write a problem statement before each one of their projects.
Next, I feel like the Software Engineering Curriculum has done a great job preparing us to work in groups after we graduate. After the introduction to programming courses, most classes have some sort of group component to them. I enjoyed having to work in groups because I learned a lot from the teammates that I worked with and with more hands, we were able to create unique solutions to the problems we were trying to solve. Also, with working in groups, we were able to practice communicating with other teammates and other faculty members in a technical manner.  This helped me understand what being a professional in the field might be like. Also, in courses we also went through professional and ethical responsibilities and learned how to be a professional in the field while still in the class room. Once again though, I feel like the curriculum has lacked an overall bigger picture. Recognizing contemporary issues were never discussed and mechanisms to learn about some issues were never discussed, as well.
Throughout the course of my degree, I have used too many resources to list, so I’ll list some of the most influential ones.

  StackOverflow (of course)
  Devoxx (YouTube)
  Spring Tips (YouTube)
  Josh Long (Spring Advocate on the Spring team)
  My senior design group: Nischay Venketram, Nathan Karasch, Nathan De Graaf, Erica Clark
  Dozens and Dozens of random blogs


Through the Devoxx and Spring Tips youtube channels, I have been able to listen to many experts speak. The Devoxx YouTube channel has content ranging from setting up a DevOps workflow to Software Architecture to Machine Learning Topics. This has been a great resource for learning about new content to use in projects. The Spring Tips YouTube channel was important in learning about Spring Boot and Microservices, which I used in my Software Architecture project. Reading Josh Long’s blog, following him on Twitter, and watching his conference talks also helped introduce me to Microservices and Spring Boot. My senior design team has taught me a lot, too. Things like a whole new programming paradigm, best practices in Node.js, how to manage and communicate with a team were learned through working with this teams.

Outside of coursework, I’ve had the opportunity to many different extracurricular activities which helped shape me as a future engineer.

  Iowa State Computer Science and Software Engieering Club (President during the 2016-2017 academic year)
  Iowa State Software Engineering Student Advisory Council (chair 2017-2018 academic year)
  Peer Mentor for the Software Engineering Learning Community (2016-2017 and 2017-2018 academic years)


These different groups were able to teach me things outside of class and show me how lifelong learning is important. I learned advanced topics in the CSE club and I was introduced to so many different tools and topics that simply could not be taught in class. Through the SE SAC, I was able to help facilitate change with the curriculum and program and hopefully make the Software Engineering program stronger in the future. Finally, as a peer mentor, I was able to help the next wave of programmers and engineers that are going to come through the SE Program.

Throughout the course of my degree, I have learned many things outside of class. I’ve leanred frameworks like Node.js, AngularJS, React, and Spring Boot. I’ve learned tools like Docker, TravisCI, Digital Ocean/Heroku/AWS. These skills have allowed me to take risks and start working on some larger projects for actual clients. I built an application that is used by a small business today. Without the knowledge gained outside of class, I would not have been able to complete this.

If I were to do my undergraduate degree over again, I would have been more focused my first semester. That was my worst semester as a college student and the only reason I did poorly because I was not focused. I also would worry less about scores and grades and more worried about a deep understanding of the material. Unfortunately, often times a deep understanding of the material won’t get you a good grade on a homework/project because you are focused on getting the points and checking boxes rather than actually understanding the material.
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/blog/2017/10/05/cumulative-education-reflection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/blog/2017/10/05/cumulative-education-reflection/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smart Sync</title>
        <description>
SmartSync is a home management system for synchronizing Internet of Things (IoT)
devices, family members’ online accounts, and other user applications. It runs
as a web application, interfacing with various services to provide a more
efficient home for the modern family. A “dashboard”-style user interface
lets the family see the status of their household at a glance. The goal of the
project was to provide a platform that allows user’s to synchronize and manage
multiple IoT devices and services. SmartSync uses a dashboard style webpage
which allows the user to view that status of multiple devices/services
simultaneously.

Throughout the course of this project, we had to consider several different
aspects. We had to consider how to design an software architecture that was
capable of interfacing with many third-party services. Another design challenge
of this project was surrounding the microservice architecture. This was a
foreign concept to the team going into this project, but we quickly learned
how to manage and configure several services running in a distributed way. We
chose the microservice architecture because it gave us the flexibility to
interface with all of of the services we needed to and allowed us to deploy
new changes and features without worrying about breaking unrelated parts
of the project.

This project was built on Spring Boot, Angular 2, and the microservice
architecture. We designed an API which allows all of the components of the
project to communicate with one another.


  
    Click here to view the architecture document
  
  
    Click here to view the server side code
  
  
    Click here to view the client side code
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2017/05/29/smartsync/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2017/05/29/smartsync/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Telligen</title>
        <description>

  
    Worked on a web application which allows measure developers to create and export health quality measures
  
  
    Helped develop an application which allows non-technical users use a domain specific programming language to create health record queries
  
  
    Developed new features, using Java Spring, Google Web Toolkit, and MySQL, which adhered to strict specifications
  
  
    Modified and implemented an open source project to increase usability in the application
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/experience/2017/05/28/telligen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/experience/2017/05/28/telligen/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salon Manager</title>
        <description>
Salon Manager is a business solution developed for a client to help manager
and organize business expenses, appointments, and client information. This
project was designed with small businesses in mind. Salon Manager provides
a “dashboard”-style UI which allows the user to view all of their information
in one glance. The goal of the project was to eliminate paper and pen business
tracking for small businesses who could not afford to upgrade to an expensive
business solution.

Salon Manager was originally built on Node.js, Angular1, and MongoDB. It also
allows the Google Calendar API to ease the stress of scheduling clients and
allow the user to take their calendar on the road. However, Salon Manager is
currently undergoing a renovation which will give a better user experience
and be easier to maintain in the future. The new Salon Manager will be built
on Spring Boot, Angular 2, and MySQL.

Though this project, I gained valuable experience in building production
worthy applications. I like to say this is the project where I learned “what
not to do” and look forward to continuing the rewrite of the project to get
it to the next level.
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2017/05/28/salonmanager/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2017/05/28/salonmanager/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iowa State Software Engineering Department</title>
        <description>

  
    Helped kickstart the peer mentor program for the Iowa State Software Engineering Department by being selected to be in the first group of peer mentors
  
  
    Guided a small group of 20 freshmen through their first year at the university
  
  
    Provided advice to freshmen, including advice about course scheduling, life on campus, and social issues
  
  
    Assisted students through their introductory to programming courses by holding small group meetings and workshops
  
  
    Presented on technical topics such as Introduction to Git and Introduction to Web Development
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/experience/2017/05/27/peermentor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/experience/2017/05/27/peermentor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wikipedia Quick Search</title>
        <description>
Wikipedia quick search is a Chrome Extension which allows users to highlight
a word on a webpage and do a quick Wikipedia search. It opens up Wikipedia
in a popup window and allows the user to see what they searched for. It is
perfect for searching people, places, teams, and events. This is the perfect
tool for when you are browsing web pages and you don’t know something in an
article.

Since it is a Chrome Extension, it uses the Chrome Message Passing API to allow
the extension to communicate with the webpage. It injects a Content Script
into the current webpage to allow the value of the highlighted text to be sent
back to the extension.

When designing this tool, speed and a minimalist design were the goals. The UI
needed to be something that did not impact the what the user was looking at on
their main screen and it needed the search needed to be fast to actually be
useful. This is why directly searching the Wikipedia website and using a
popup window were the best choices.
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2016/06/01/wikipedia-quick-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/project/2016/06/01/wikipedia-quick-search/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iowa State Computer Science and Sofware Engineering Club</title>
        <description>

  
    Unanimously elected President of the Iowa State Computer Science and Software Engineering club by my peers in the club
  
  
    Planned and hosted one of the largest club events in recent history; with over 110 people in attendance
  
  
    Tripled the end-of-the-year attendance compared to the previous year
  
  
    Worked closely with factuly, industry members, and students to plan and execute events
  
  
    Presented several technical presentations, including talks on Spring Boot and
the MEAN stack.
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>www.jackcmeyer.com/experience/2016/05/28/cse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jackcmeyer.com/experience/2016/05/28/cse/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
