<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Meyer</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 19:36:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 19:36:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smart Sync</title>
        <description>

  
    Built with Spring Boot and Angular 2, using a microservice architecture to give faster response times to the user.
  
  
    Gives users the ability to create a household to synchronize calendars and to-do lists
  
  
    Includes a fully customizable, dashboard like interface for the user to view their household’s information
  
  
    Collaborated with 3 other groups members to design, implement, and test features in the application
  
  
    Click here to view the architecture document
  
  
    Click here to view the server side code
  
  
    Click here to view the client side code
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2017/05/29/smartsync/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2017/05/29/smartsync/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Telligen</title>
        <description>

  
    Worked on a web application which allows measure developers to create and export health quality measures
  
  
    Helped develop an application which allows non-technical users use a domain specific programming language to create health record queries
  
  
    Developed new features, using Java Spring, Google Web Toolkit, and MySQL, which adhered to strict specifications
  
  
    Modified and implemented an open source project to increase usability in the application
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience/2017/05/28/telligen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience/2017/05/28/telligen/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salon Manager</title>
        <description>

  
    A business solution developed for a client to help manage and organize business expenses, appointments, and client     information.
  
  
    Uses the Google Calendar API to ease the stress of scheduling clients.
  
  
    Includes a Mongo database to quickly fetch and organize client information.
  
  
    Accurately tracks business expenses, prints monthly and yearly reports for end of the year taxes.
  
  
    Currently working on converting the application from NodeJS/Angular/MongoDB to Java (Spring Boot), Angular 2, and MySQL. This should create a better user experience for the user and be more maintainable in the future. You can follow the transition here.
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2017/05/28/salonmanager/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2017/05/28/salonmanager/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iowa State Software Engineering Department</title>
        <description>

  
    Helped kickstart the peer mentor program for the Iowa State Software Engineering department by being selected to be in the first group of peer mentors
  
  
    Guided and mentored a small group of 20 freshmen through their first year at the university
  
  
    Provided advice to freshmen, including advice about course scheduling, life on campus, and social issues
  
  
    Assisted students with their troubles in their introduction to programming courses, including Introduction to Python, C, and Java
  
  
    Presented on technical topics such as Python Tips and Tricks, Introduction to GIT, and Introduction to HTML/CSS
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience/2017/05/27/peermentor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience/2017/05/27/peermentor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wikipedia Quick Search</title>
        <description>

  
    Google Chrome Extension which allows a user to highlight a word on a webpage and do a quick Wikipedia search.
  
  
    Uses the Chrome Message Passing API to allow the extension to communicate with the webpage.
  
  
    Injects a Content Script into the current webpage to allow the value of the highlighted text to be sent back to the extension.
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2016/06/01/wikipedia-quick-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2016/06/01/wikipedia-quick-search/</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iowa State Computer Science and Sofware Engineering Club</title>
        <description>

  
    Unanimously elected President of the Iowa State Computer Science and Software Engineering club by my peers in the club
  
  
    Planned and hosted one of the largest club events in recent history; with over 110 people in attendance
  
  
    Tripled the end-of-the-year attendance compared to the previous year
  
  
    Worked closely with factuly, industry members, and students to plan and execute events
  
  
    Presented several technical presentations, including talks on Spring Boot and
the MEAN stack.
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience/2016/05/28/cse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience/2016/05/28/cse/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Super America</title>
        <description>

  
    Responded to customer complaints and swiftly resolved their issues to ensure and maintain customer satisfaction.
  
  
    Assisted with checking in vendors to guarantee the correctness of their delivery of up to $10,000 in product.
  
  
    Interacted with corporate managers to ensure the functionality of the store is to their operational standards.
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience/2015/08/01/superamerica/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience/2015/08/01/superamerica/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Prague Basketball</title>
        <description>

  
    Assisted in facilitating basketball camps for approximately 70 student-athletes, aging from kindergarten to high school sophomores
  
  
    Demonstrated, instructed, and clarified basketball skills and drills for small groups of 5-15 players
  
  
    Prepared practice plans to promote the improvement of the player and of the team.
  
  
    Identified weaknesses of the players and of the team and suggested new ideas to eliminate their weakness.
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience/2015/06/01/coach/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience/2015/06/01/coach/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
